Inventory of the Keith E. Eiler papers, 1880-2003
Hoover Institution Archives
Keith E. Eiler papers
1880-2003
2005C38
Hoover Institution Archives
30 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 6 card file boxes, 1 motion picture film reel (13.6 linear feet)
Correspondence, notes, collected writings, photocopies of military records and collected correspondence, printed matter, and photographs related to the career of General Albert C. Wedemeyer, commander of American forces in China during World War II. Used as research material for the book Wedemeyer on War and Peace (Stanford, 1987) edited by Keith E. Eiler, and for an unpublished biography of Wedemeyer. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Eiler, Keith E., 1920-
Access
Collection is open for research. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2005.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternate Forms Available
Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Related Materials
Albert C. (Albert Coady) Wedemeyer papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Biographical Note
Keith E. Eiler was a scholar of military mobilization and United States military history and the biographer of General Albert C. Wedemeyer. In addition to his academic life as an American historian and Hoover Institution fellow, Eiler was a lieutenant colonel in the United States Army. He was born in Monowi, Nebraska, in 1920. After graduating from West Point in 1944, Eiler served in the 80th Infantry Division for the Third U.S. Army in Europe during World War II. After being wounded in the Battle of the Bulge, Eiler became an engineer for the Armed Forces Special Weapons Project. From 1950 to 1951, Eiler was the aide-de-camp to General Wedemeyer during Wedemeyer's term as commander of the Sixth U.S. Army at the Presidio of San Francisco.
Before retiring from military service in 1965, Eiler served with the Eighth U.S. Army in Korea, commanded an engineer combat battalion in Germany, became the assistant director of military construction with the Office of the Chief of Engineers, and served with the army general staff in the Office of the Chief of Staff and the headquarters of the Army Forces Far East in Tokyo. In addition, Eiler was an instructor and assistant professor of mathematics at West Point from 1954 to 1958.
As the biographer of General Wedemeyer, Eiler conducted research at the Hoover Institution after Wedemeyer's papers were deposited in the archives, becoming a Hoover fellow in 1983. In 1987, Eiler edited Wedemeyer on War and Peace, a selection of Wedemeyer's writings that Eiler called a "warm-up for the biography" in a letter to Joseph Alsop (box 7, folder 7). Although Eiler never finished his biography of Wedemeyer, he conducted extensive research on Wedemeyer's life, often visiting Wedemeyer to interview him.
In 1997, Eiler published Mobilizing America: Robert P. Patterson and the War Effort, 1940-1945, which won the Hoover Institution's Uncommon Book Award in 1999. Eiler passed away in 2005 at the age of 85.
Sources:
Bethell, Tom. "Keith Eiler, Officer and Gentleman." Hoover Digest 2006. Accessed through: http://www.hoover.org/research/keith-eiler-officer-and-gentleman
"Hoover Institution Research Fellow Keith E. Eiler dies at age 85." Accessed through: http://www.hoover.org/press-releases/hoover-institution-research-fellow-keith-e-eiler-dies-age-85
Scope and Content of Collection
The Keith E. Eiler papers contain Eiler's research and writings on the career of General Albert C. Wedemeyer, commander of American forces in China during World War II.
The Albert C. Wedemeyer file consists of Eiler's research materials for his unfinished biography on Wedemeyer and the book Wedemeyer on War and Peace. The research materials and related documents are divided into three groups: general, subject file, and files on individuals. As Wedemeyer's biographer and friend, Eiler often met with the general to discuss Wedemeyer's life and views (box 5, folders 5-6). In addition to interviewing Wedemeyer, Eiler spoke to many individuals associated with Wedemeyer at various stages of his life, including West Point classmates and those who served with him in World War II. These interviews, along with correspondence and subject material, can be found in the files on individuals. Although these research files mainly contain photocopies of Wedemeyer's correspondence, printed matter, photocopied military documents, or the correspondence of Eiler concerning his research, the files also contain a number of original documents related to Wedemeyer and his family. Since Eiler conducted much of his research at the Hoover Institution, many of his notes were taken on note paper with the Hoover Institution letterhead, and photocopies of documents often contain a Hoover copyright statement.
In 1987, Eiler was the editor of a book of Wedemeyer's writings. The Wedemeyer on War and Peace file contains drafts of the manuscript, correspondence, research, corrections by Robert Hessen, and notes.
Additional research on Wedemeyer, including a detailed chronology of his life, can be found in the Card files and note cards, which also contain a bibliography related to Robert P. Patterson, the subject of Eiler's book Mobilizing America.
For sound recordings of interviews, as well as the film "Catalina scenes, Echols-Curl," see the Sound recordings and motion picture films.
Arrangement
The collection contains materials which fall under four series: Albert C. Wedemeyer file, Wedemeyer on War and Peace file, Card files and note cards, and Sound recordings and motion picture films. Although the collection is not physically arranged in series, the series description can serve as a guide to the materials.
Index to Major Groups
1-16, 18, 20-31 Albert C. Wedemeyer file, 1880-2003. Includes correspondence, interviews, notes, printed matter, and military records related to Wedemeyer and used as research for an unfinished biography and Wedemeyer on War and Peace. Contains three sub-series: general, subject file, and files on individuals.
17-20 Wedemeyer on War and Peace file, 1938-1987. Includes drafts, research, notes, and correspondence related to the manuscript.
32-37 Card files and note cards, undated. Contains notes, address files, bibliographies, and a chronology of Wedemeyer's life.
1, 31 Sound recordings and motion picture films, 1974-1987, undated. Sound recordings of interviews and the film "Catalina scenes, Echols-Curl."
United States. Army--Officers.; Wedemeyer, Albert C. (Albert Coady), 1896-1989.; China--Foreign relations--United States.; United States--Foreign relations--China.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--China.
- Albert C. Wedemeyer file (Folder 1)
  - Subject file (Folder 1)
    - A-bomb, 1995-1998 (Folder 1: 1)
    - AEI (American Economic Foundation), 1963 (Folder 1: 2)
    - Air power, 1982-2000 (Folder 1: 3)
    - American Heritage, 1982-1983 (Folder 1: 4)
      Scope and Contents note
      Includes interview of Wedemeyer by Eiler
    - Anti-Communism, 1996-1999 (Folder 1: 5)
    - Anti-Semitism, 1955-2002 (Folder 1: 6)
    - Ardennes, 1986-1996 (Folder 1: 7)
    - Atomic, 1957-1961 (Folder 1: 8)
    - Axiom, undated (Folder 1: 9)
    - Berlin airlift, 1949-1979 (Folder 1: 10)
    - Bohemian Club, 1965-1987 (Folder 1: 11)
    - British officers, 1948-1962 (Folder 1: 12)
    - Casablanca, 1943, undated (Folder 1: 13)
      Includes itinerary and diary of Wedemeyer for Casablanca Conference
    - Burma Star, 1976-1981 (Folder 1: 14)
    - China, 1950-1999 (Folder 1: 15)
    - China Connection, 1989 (Folder 1: 16)
    - Chinese, 1986-1988, undated (Folder 1: 17)
- Catalina scenes, Echols-Curl motion picture film, circa 1943 (Film Shelf)
  Color film footage of Catalina Island and Newport Beach, CA circa 1943. Includes scenes on boats and on the island, as well as footage of an unidentified Asian couple. Use copy (DVD) available. Hoover ID: 2005C38.1
- Albert C. Wedemeyer file (Folder 2-16)
  - Subject file (Folder 2-3)
    - Chinese officers, 1946-1994 (Folder 2: 1)
    - CIA (Central Intelligence Agency), 1999 (Folder 2: 2)
    - Civil-military, 1948-1974 (Folder 2: 3)
    - Cold War, 1997-2000 (Folder 2: 4)
    - Communism, 1946-1968 (Folder 2: 5)
    - Culp films, 1985-1990 (Folder 2: 6)
    - Decision making, 2000 (Folder 2: 7)
    - Dixie Mission, 1963-1997 (Folder 2: 8)
    - Espionage, 1976-1991 (Folder 2: 9)
    - Flying Tigers, 1945-1991 (Folder 2: 10)
      Includes photograph signed by Wedemeyer. Includes pictorial magazine of the Flying Tigers
    - Geopolitics, 1987-1988 (Folder 2: 11)
    - German officers, 1950-1976 (Folder 2: 12)
    - Hess case, 1984-1991 (Folder 2: 13)
      Includes letter from Wedemeyer to Eiler
    - Hiss case, 1945-1996 (Folder 2: 14)
    - Husky, 1968-1970 (Folder 2: 15)
    - Indo-China, 1955-1982 (Folder 2: 16)
      Includes thesis of Jeremy Horne
    - Isolationism, 1956-1976 (Folder 2: 17)
    - Japanese Army China, 1959-1967 (Folder 3: 1)
    - Japan occupation, 1999 (Folder 3: 2)
    - Korean War, 1990-1993 (Folder 3: 3)
    - Kriegsakademie, 1936-1988 (Folder 3: 4)
      Includes memorandum for Eiler from Wedemeyer, and list of and letters from Wedemeyer's classmates
    - Victory Plan leak, 1958-1997 (Folder 3: 5)
  - General (Folder 3-7)
    - Family (Folder 3)
      - Wedemeyer, Frederick, 1880-1987 (Folder 3: 6)
      - Wedemeyer, Dade (Elizabeth), 1972-1996 (Folder 3: 7)
      - Coady, Michael, 1900-1986 (Folder 3: 8)
        Grandfather of Wedemeyer
    - Mission (1947), 1947-1997 (Folder 3: 9)
    - Genealogical material, 1924-1986 (Folder 4: 1)
      Includes correspondence of Albert C. Wedemeyer
    - Benning, 1959-1975 (Folder 4: 2)
    - Philippines, 1961-1976 (Folder 4: 3)
    - Clippings, 1946-1983 (Folder 4: 4)
    - Omaha, 1962-1987 (Folder 4: 5)
    - July 9, 1986 file, 1896, 1971 (Folder 4: 6)
      Includes Wedemeyer's explanation of birth year in records
    - Family, 1911-1972, undated (Folder 4: 7)
      Includes original copy of invitation to Wedemeyer's wedding, photographs of Wedemeyer's family, and correspondence
    - Retirement, 1951 (Folder 4: 8)
    - School, 1945-1991 (Folder 4: 9)
    - West Point years, 1965-1968 (Folder 4: 10)
    - Church and baptism, 1986-1987 (Folder 4: 11)
    - Diary, 1942 (Folder 4: 12)
    - Miscellaneous, 1956-1994 (Folder 4: 13)
    - Copyright for Wedemeyer papers, 1999 (Folder 4: 14)
    - Nebraska Navy card of Wedemeyer, undated (Folder 4: 15)
    - Documents sent to Eiler from Wedemeyer, 1975-1983 (Folder 5: 1)
    - War Department files, 1920-1951 (Folder 5: 2)
    - Photographs of Wedemeyer and staff in Chungking from General Chang, 1987, undated (Folder 5: 3)
    - Friendly views, 1945-1984 (Folder 5: 4)
    - Interviews of Albert C. Wedemeyer, 1977-1989 (Folder 5: 5-6)
    - Obituaries and death, 1989 (Folder 6: 1-2)
      Includes will
    - Photographs, 1925-1988, undated (Folder 6: 3)
    - Bibliography, 1984-1987, undated (Folder 6: 4)
    - Biographies of Wedemeyer, 1945-1983 (Folder 6: 5)
    - Cadet 201 files, 1917-1986 (Folder 6: 6)
    - Correspondence of Eiler, 1983-1991 (Folder 6: 7)
    - Miscellaneous interviews about Wedemeyer, 1980-1993, undated (Folder 7: 1)
    - Anecdotes, 1953-1981 (Folder 7: 2)
    - Family, 1916-2003 (Folder 7: 3)
    - Albert A. Wedemeyer, 1931-1986 (Folder 7: 4)
      Includes photograph
  - Files on individuals (Folder 7-11)
    - Acheson, Dean, 1952-1998 (Folder 7: 5)
    - Allman, Norwood, 1959 (Folder 7: 6)
    - Alsop, Joseph W., 1950-1988 (Folder 7: 7)
    - Aurand, Henry, 1948-1958 (Folder 7: 8)
    - Baldwin, Hanson, 1950 (Folder 7: 9)
    - Barr, David, undated (Folder 7: 10)
    - Barrett, D., 1951-1971 (Folder 7: 11)
      Includes photographs and original letter from Barrett to Wedemeyer
    - Bliss, Tasker Howard, 1922-1980 (Folder 7: 12)
    - Baruch, Bernard, 1950-1952 (Folder 7: 13)
    - Baumer, William H., 1980 (Folder 7: 14)
    - Bishop, Max, 1985 (Folder 7: 15)
    - Black, Virginia, 1984-1989 (Folder 7: 16)
      Daughter of J. Arthur Duff
    - Breul, Sally D., 1980 (Folder 7: 17)
    - Brink, 1949 (Folder 7: 18)
    - Brockman, Ronald, 1981-1985 (Folder 7: 19)
    - Browder, Earl, 1945 (Folder 7: 20)
    - Brower, Charles, 1982-2002 (Folder 7: 21)
    - Buckley, William, 1972-1973 (Folder 7: 22)
    - Buffett, Leila, 1980 (Folder 7: 23)
    - Burdick, Charles, 1986 (Folder 7: 24)
    - Byroade, Henry, 1988 (Folder 7: 25)
    - Calder, A. Bland, 1971 (Folder 7: 26)
    - Carr, William G., 1986 (Folder 7: 27)
    - Carsun Chang, 1974 (Folder 7: 28)
    - Caraway, Paul W., 1981, undated (Folder 7: 29)
    - Carter, Marshall, 1972-1984 (Folder 7: 30)
    - Chamberlain, John, 1977-1990 (Folder 7: 31)
    - Caughey, J. Hart, 1992 (Folder 7: 32)
    - Chennault, Claire, 1944-1990 (Folder 8: 1-2)
    - Chiang Kai-shek, 1945-1980 (Folder 8: 3)
      See also Box 31
    - Chiang Ching-Kuo, 1953 (Folder 8: 4)
    - Chinese correspondents, 1962-1986 (Folder 8: 5)
      Includes letters of Tingfu Tsiang, Ta-wei Yu, and Hu Shih
    - Davies, John P., 1943-1969 (Folder 8: 6)
    - Churchill, Winston, 1968-1994 (Folder 8: 7)
    - Clarke, Bruce C., 1987 (Folder 8: 8)
    - Clarke, Carter, 1975-1986 (Folder 8: 9)
    - Clay, Lucius D., 1946 (Folder 8: 10)
    - James, D. Clayton, 1971-1986 (Folder 8: 11)
    - Clifford, Robert L., 1988-1989 (Folder 8: 12)
    - Cline, Ray, 1983 (Folder 8: 13)
    - Clubb, O. Edmund, circa 1945-1947 (Folder 8: 14)
    - Collins, Joe Lawton, 1947-1987 (Folder 8: 15)
    - Colville, John, 1985-1987 (Folder 8: 16)
      Includes draft of chapter fragment for Wedemeyer on War and Peace
    - Cooke, Charles M. ("Savvy"), 1953, undated (Folder 8: 17)
    - Corcoran, Thomas G., 1987 (Folder 8: 18)
    - Craig, Gordon, undated (Folder 8: 19)
    - Cray, Ed, 1985 (Folder 8: 20)
    - Creel, George, 1969 (Folder 8: 21)
    - Crone, Richard I., 1983-1985 (Folder 8: 22)
    - Davidson, Garrison, 1980 (Folder 8: 23)
    - Devers, Jacob, 1958-1976 (Folder 8: 24)
    - Carton de Wiart, Adrian, 1947-1950 (Folder 8: 25)
    - Dickey, J., 1987-1988 (Folder 8: 26)
    - Donovan, William, 1945-1949 (Folder 8: 27)
    - Doolittle, J. H., 1984 (Folder 8: 28)
    - Dorn, Frank, 1981-1984 (Folder 8: 29)
    - Drumright, undated (Folder 8: 30)
    - Dunn, Peter M., 1945-1985 (Folder 8: 31)
    - Dunn, Walter Scott, Jr., 1975-1987 (Folder 9: 1)
    - Eaker, Ira C., 1977 (Folder 9: 2)
    - Embick, 1919-1981 (Folder 9: 3)
      Includes original correspondence of Wedemeyer and Stanley Dunbar Embick
    - Eisenhower, Dwight, 1952-1988 (Folder 9: 4)
    - Emmerson, John K., 1951-1970 (Folder 9: 5)
    - Enloe, Cortez, 1990-1995 (Folder 9: 6)
    - Essman, Graydon, 1988-1989 (Folder 9: 7)
    - Fairbank, John King, 1982 (Folder 9: 8)
    - Fanning, Loius, 1989 (Folder 9: 9)
    - Fertig, Lawrence, 1962-1970 (Folder 9: 10)
    - Fitch, George A., 1947-1989 (Folder 9: 11)
      Includes letters of Edith Swapp
    - Fleming, Thomas, 1986-1988 (Folder 9: 12)
    - Ford, John, 1964-1970 (Folder 9: 13)
    - Forrestal, James, 1949-1992 (Folder 9: 14-15)
    - Fuller, J. F. C., 1949-1958 (Folder 9: 16)
    - Byrnes, James F., 1977 (Folder 9: 17-18)
      Dissertation by John William Partin
    - Gallagher, Leila and Phil, 1963 (Folder 9: 19)
    - Gandhi, undated (Folder 9: 20)
    - Gauss, undated (Folder 9: 21)
    - Graham, Thomas E., 1987-1988 (Folder 9: 22)
    - Gray, Gordon, 1949 (Folder 9: 23)
    - Groves, Leslie, 1965-1969 (Folder 9: 24)
    - Gruenther, Alfred, 1949 (Folder 9: 25)
    - Russell Randall (Folder 10)
      - Memoir, 1976 (Folder 10: 1)
      - Diary, photocopies, 1943-1945, undated (Folder 10: 2)
    - Ungern, Reginald and Gallagher, Philip, correspondence and related documents, 1947-1974 (Folder 10: 3-4)
    - Kirkpatrick, Charles E. (Folder 10-11)
      - Manuscript on army mobilization planning in 1941, 1988, undated (Folder 10: 5)
      - Papers on the Victory Plan, 1941-1942, undated (Folder 11: 1)
    - MacArthur, Douglas, 1943-1952 (Folder 11: 2)
      Documents from MacArthur archives
    - Aurand, Herny, 1978, undated (Folder 11: 3)
      Includes Rice, Roads and Robbery typescript
    - Jacobsen, Mark, 1989, undated (Folder 11: 4)
    - Johnson, Erik, 1998 (Folder 11: 5)
    - Caraway, Paul W., 1989, undated (Folder 11: 6)
      Documents from Caraway archives
  - Subject file (Folder 11)
    - Soviet Volunteers in China, circa 1977 (Folder 11: 7)
  - Files on individuals (Folder 11-16)
    - Marshall, George C., 1944-1949 (Folder 11: 8)
    - Yu, Ta-wei, circa 1980-1987, undated (Folder 11: 9)
      Includes documents in Chinese
    - Jones, Orren L., 1983-1984 (Folder 12: 1)
    - Ochsner, Alton, 1963-1972 (Folder 12: 2)
    - O'Hara, Tom, 1957 (Folder 12: 3)
    - Olmsted, George, 1968-1988 (Folder 12: 4)
    - Osmanski, Frank A., 1985 (Folder 12: 5)
    - Osmanski, Frank A., 1985 (Folder 12: 5)
    - Packard, David, 1988 (Folder 12: 6)
    - Patterson, Edward, 1986 (Folder 12: 7)
    - Patton, George and Beatrice, 1942-1985 (Folder 12: 8)
    - Pee, Peter, 1953-1984 (Folder 12: 9-11)
      Includes photograph and writings
    - Peterkin, Wilbur, 1976-1989 (Folder 12: 12)
    - Peterson, Edward N., 1983 (Folder 12: 13)
    - Pihl, Paul, 1986 (Folder 12: 14)
    - Pogue, Forrest, 1957-1996 (Folder 12: 15)
    - Pope Paul, 1967-1975 (Folder 12: 16)
    - Radford, Arthur, 1953 (Folder 12: 17)
    - Randall, Russell, 1980-1985, undated (Folder 12: 18)
    - Ratay, John P., 1969-1976 (Folder 12: 19)
    - Reardon, Mark, 1971-1991 (Folder 12: 20)
    - Rhee, Syngman, 1947-1965 (Folder 12: 21)
    - Rickenbacker, William F., 1948-1990 (Folder 12: 22)
    - Ridgway, Matthew B., 1987-1993 (Folder 13: 1)
    - Roberts, Frank, circa 1956-1987 (Folder 13: 2)
    - Rogers, William P., 1972-1973 (Folder 13: 3)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin, 1991-1997, undated (Folder 13: 4)
    - Rowe, David, 1946-1971 (Folder 13: 5)
    - Rusk, Dean, 1969 (Folder 13: 6)
    - Shultz, George, 1989 (Folder 13: 7)
    - SEAC (South East Asia Command) veterans, 1988 (Folder 13: 8)
    - Sebree, Edmund B., 1964 (Folder 13: 9)
    - Seno, Sadao, 1980-2000 (Folder 13: 10)
    - Service, John S., 1951-1999 (Folder 13: 11)
    - Shah, Konsin, 1957-1985 (Folder 13: 12)
    - Shen, J. C. H., 1972-1979 (Folder 13: 13)
    - Shepley, Jim, 1969 (Folder 13: 14)
    - Sibley, Alden, 1981 (Folder 13: 15)
    - Simpson, William H., 1966-1979 (Folder 13: 16)
    - Smith, Ralph, 1977-1988 (Folder 13: 17)
    - Smith, Truman, 1949-1983 (Folder 13: 18)
    - Snow, Edgar, 1989 (Folder 13: 19)
    - Sokolsky, George E., 1948 (Folder 13: 20)
    - Solberg, Carl, 1986-1987 (Folder 13: 21)
    - Soong, 1971-1985, undated (Folder 13: 22)
    - Soong, Ching Ling, 1945-1988, undated (Folder 13: 23)
    - Sparrow, Herbert G., 1981-1985 (Folder 13: 24)
    - Spellman, Francis, 1956-1967 (Folder 13: 25)
    - Spotswood, Denis, 1985 (Folder 13: 26)
    - Standley, 1976 (Folder 13: 27)
    - Stanford, 1988 (Folder 13: 28)
    - Stauffenberg, Claus von, 1947-1975 (Folder 13: 29)
    - Stauffenberg, Claus von, 1947-1975 (Folder 13: 29)
    - Stettinius, Edward R., Jr., 1947 (Folder 13: 30)
    - Stilwell, Joseph, 1944-1995 (Folder 14: 1)
    - Stimson, Henry L. (Folder 14)
      - General, 1948-1990 (Folder 14: 2)
      - Diary, photocopy, 1942-1945 (Folder 14: 3)
    - Stodter, John Hughes, 1968-1970 (Folder 14: 4)
    - Stoler, Mark, 1981-1993 (Folder 14: 5)
    - Strange, Joseph L., 1982-1983 (Folder 14: 6)
    - Stratemeyer, George E., 1949-1956 (Folder 14: 7)
    - Strauss, Lewis L., 1953 (Folder 14: 8)
    - Stuart, John L., 1948-1990, undated (Folder 14: 9)
    - Stueck, William, 1982-1999 (Folder 14: 10)
    - Sullivan, William M., 1972 (Folder 14: 11)
    - Sultan, Dan, 1945 (Folder 14: 12)
    - Sun, Li-jen, 1949-1951 (Folder 14: 13)
    - Halder, Franz, 1960-1972 (Folder 14: 14)
    - Handy, Thomas, 1980 (Folder 14: 15)
    - Hansell, Haywood S., 1973-1986 (Folder 14: 16)
    - Harriman, W. Averell, 1971-1984 (Folder 14: 17)
    - Hart, John, 1959-1960 (Folder 14: 18)
    - Hart, B. H. Liddell, 1962-1969 (Folder 14: 19)
    - Hartness, Harlan N., 1984 (Folder 14: 20)
    - Hearn, Thomas G., 1980 (Folder 14: 21)
    - Heerema, Pieter, 1978-1979 (Folder 14: 22)
    - Heppner, Richard, 1957-2001 (Folder 14: 23)
      Includes correspondence with Elizabeth McIntosh
    - Hoover, Herbert, 1951-2000 (Folder 14: 24)
    - Hoover, J. Edgar, 1960 (Folder 14: 25)
    - Hopkins, H., undated (Folder 14: 26)
    - Hornbeck, Stanley K., 1953-1961 (Folder 14: 27)
    - Huang, J. L., 1981 (Folder 14: 28)
    - Hubbard, 1945-1991 (Folder 14: 29)
    - Hunter, Charles N., 1962-1971, undated (Folder 14: 30)
    - Hurley, Patrick, 1945-1957 (Folder 14: 31)
    - Huston, M. N., 1987 (Folder 14: 32)
    - Hutchin, Claire E., 1947-1987 (Folder 15: 1)
      Includes original correspondence of Hutchin from 1947
    - Jones, Herbert M., 1984 (Folder 15: 2)
    - Jones, John M., 1986 (Folder 15: 3)
    - Jones, Norman E., 1990-1991 (Folder 15: 4)
    - Judd, Walter H., 1945-1989 (Folder 15: 5)
    - Kataoka, Tetsuya, 1959-1975 (Folder 15: 6)
    - Kennan, George F., 1950-1984 (Folder 15: 7-8)
    - Keyes, Fenton, 1986-1987 (Folder 15: 9)
    - Kilbourne, Charles E., 1963-1988 (Folder 15: 10)
    - Kimmel, Thomas K., 1954-1992 (Folder 15: 11)
    - King, Ernest, 1963-1971 (Folder 15: 12)
    - Kirkpatrick, Charles E., correspondence, 1988-1991 (Folder 15: 13)
    - Kissinger, Henry, 1974-1975 (Folder 15: 14)
    - Kohlberg, Alfred, 1944-1945 (Folder 15: 15)
    - Kubek, Anthony, 1986, undated (Folder 15: 16)
    - Kuhn, Irene, 1988 (Folder 15: 17)
    - K'ung, 1951-1978 (Folder 15: 18)
      See also Box 16, folder 1
    - Lattimore, Owen, 1938-1992 (Folder 15: 19)
    - Larrabee, Eric, 1986-1987 (Folder 15: 20)
    - LaVarre, William, 1983-1988 (Folder 15: 21)
    - Leahy, William D., 1945-1955 (Folder 15: 22)
    - Lee, Orient, 1979-1980 (Folder 15: 23)
    - Lemnitzer, Lyman L., 1987 (Folder 15: 24)
    - Li, Tsung-jen, 1965, undated (Folder 15: 25)
    - Liang, Chin-tung, 1972 (Folder 15: 26)
    - Ligutti, Luigi G., 1975 (Folder 15: 27)
    - K'ung, L. K., 1983-1995 (Folder 16: 1)
      See also Box 15, folder 18
    - Li, Tsung-jen, 1947 (Folder 16: 2)
    - Lincoln, Lawrence J., 1944-1993 (Folder 16: 3)
    - Lindbergh, Charles, 1948-1950 (Folder 16: 4)
    - Longworth, Alice, 1970 (Folder 16: 5)
    - Lowry, Charles W., 1958-1986 (Folder 16: 6)
    - Luce, 1991 (Folder 16: 7)
    - McAfee, William, 1986-1997 (Folder 16: 8)
    - MacArthur, Douglas, 1949-1995 (Folder 16: 9)
    - McCarthy, Frank, 1970-1986 (Folder 16: 10)
    - McCarthy, Joe, 1952-1967 (Folder 16: 11)
    - McCloy, John J., 1983-1992 (Folder 16: 12-13)
    - McClure, Robert B., 1953 (Folder 16: 14)
    - McCune, Shannon, 1987 (Folder 16: 15)
    - McNichols, Larry, 1983-1984 (Folder 16: 16)
    - Mansfield, Mike, 1962 (Folder 16: 17)
    - Mao, Tse-tung (Mao Zedong), 1971-2000 (Folder 16: 18)